Please stand up.
Please give them a big hand.
you
Hello everyone, welcome to the Natatorium at the Nanjing Olympic Sports Centre.
We've arrived at the final individual event, the men's 10 metre platform.
Perhaps the most prestigious event of them all.
Don't forget though, this is not the traditional finale to the diving competition.
We've still got the international team event to come, which is a real innovation here at the Youth Olympic Games.
For now though, we're up on that really tall platform and that means we're staging a fascinating rematch in one of the big rivalries that provided some excellent competition here in the pool.
The host nation's Yang Hao is looking to emulate the great Xu Bo who won double gold at these games four years ago in Singapore and has gone on to world championship Olympic success.
However, Rodrigo Diego López pushed Yang all the way in the three-meter event before the Chinese diver grabbed the gold.
They didn't feast each other over 10 meters.
Another excellent competition on the cards here.
Of course, Wu Shengping has already won both women's individual titles here in Nanjing.
Can Yang Hao make another double-double for the world's greatest diving nation?
And of course it would be right here in front of their own knowledgeable and passionate fans.
Good crowd here already in this auditorium.
Let's sort out the format in this preliminary competition.
Nine rounds of diving ahead of these 11 divers.
It's a testing session.
The first four rounds comprise of dives with a total degree of difficulty limited to 7.6.
In reality, there'll be a lot less than that.
The marks from these are carried forward into the final, so this preliminary really does count towards the medals.
After that, the divers move on to the more ambitious dives, a further five rounds with no limit on the degree of difficulty.
In many ways, that's where the show begins.
Judges are cloistered away from each other and from everybody else.
Remember, seven judges, top and bottom two are struck off.
We're left with the middle three that count.
They're added together multiplied by the degree of difficulty and that is what you shall get.
As we said, eleven competitors.
Yang Hao will be second up and will get the biggest cheer of course but keep an eye out for number nine from Mexico,
He has a good rivalry with the Chinese diver.
And I imagine the Singaporeans will get some support here.
We've already heard some cheers for him as we went through the introductions here in the natatorium.
Nervous moment for these divers.
Remember some of them very young indeed, 15, 16 years of age.
For a lot of them, this is the biggest stage they've been on.
And the highest platform of course, after the three meter springboard, we've now moved on to the ten meter.
And all these dives early on will be fairly simple in terms of dive difficulty.
Ones, one point nines, twos, that sort of thing.
Afterwards it will get quite interesting.
Yang, for example, has gone for 3.4 and 3.5.
Some of these divers just have a little sing-along.
These headphones just to block out the PA, the crowd, the other competitors.
Get yourself into the zone.
Rehearse your dives in your head.
Get the tape on to protect the wrist as you enter the water from such a height.
and we're very close to getting underway here in the men's 10 meter platform the preliminary dives nine rounds nine dives they have to perfect and they'll be breathing deeply at this point they've been practicing for quite some time we'll start with Philipp
Tchaikovsky, fifth in the three meter platform.
He's competing in both these disciplines.
Van from Kiev, the Ukrainian.
Once we get underway, then these dives will come thick and fast.
Let's pause a moment and wait for this first dive of the competition.
Arm stand forward somersault, 1.9 the difficulty.
Well a simple dive, executed well by the Ukrainian.
There is of course a trade-off between the amount of difficulty and how easy you can get through the dive of course.
A pretty decent dive, kept it very straight, good in that height position.
as well 45.6 now for the crowd to get behind this man here 1.6 the difficulty forward one and a half somersault the crowd like it nicely done from the Chinese athlete good attack
Certainly I think the judges will like that one.
Lines almost across the board, 43.2 for the Chinese diver.
Daniel Jensen.
North Norway, the 18-year-old with a house and forward somersault.
1.9 the difficulty.
The first time out of the way for the European junior champion who got the bronze in those championships in the 10 meter.
He goes into third.
So impressed the judges there.
Seven and a halfs are on the marks.
He'll take forward 42.75.
Still the Ukrainian who is on top of the pile.
Now the German, Tino Bartel.
An inward one and a half somersault.
A difficulty of two.
That's the most difficult dive we've seen so far in these early stages.
Executed it pretty well.
Possibly getting the entry completely right.
head on the knees that's what the judges like to see and a pretty good entry as well and the judges will give him eight and seven and a half so the degree of difficulty means that he gets 47 points and goes top of the pile at the moment and the Armenian this is another two degree of difficulty dive the inward one and a half somersaults
It looked good from here.
Nice.
A little straight.
The judges weren't so impressed.
They have marked him down a little bit.
Sixes.
Total score of 36 puts him fifth out of five.
Now the Canadian, Philippe Gagne.
Excellent bronze medal at the three metre events.
This is a forward one and a half somersault.
One most difficult dive, just a degree of difficulty of 1.6.
Again, that's what we'd just like to see.
The legs and the face brought together.
Seven and a half, 34.4 into sixth place.
And the Egyptian.
The Egyptians have two divers here.
Just a forward dive.
a simple dive nicely executed degree of difficulty just one and a half getting his face that close to the legs that's what the judges like to see and modest scores six point five and sevens but of course the difficulty not so hard and he goes into seventh place with 30 points
now the Colombian Kevin Garcia Alvarez a forward one and a half somersault 1.6 the degree of difficulty nice entry these dives early on are the simpler dives but remember the scores going forward to the final round later on today so it is important to get these right before you start your showboating
and sevens from the judges and the six point fives scrubbed through 33.6 taking him to seventh place now then here is the mexican the big rival to the chinese rodrigo diego lopez forward one and a half seven salt
Not too difficultly, 1.6 degree of difficulty.
Not quite making the position.
A little bit more flexibility there.
36 to score, seven and a halfs from the judges all the way through.
And that's a modest from the Mexican, but there's lots of rounds to go.
Now the Frenchman mixes Jeandard with a forward one and a half somersault.
An exact carbon copy of the Mexicans dive.
That was a little bit sharper.
Nice speed on the dive there.
They tuck in nicely as well.
Sevens from judges.
Six point five, one seven point five, they won't cope.
And that's into eight for the Frenchman.
That's but by no means least, we have the Singaporean.
Is it Jonathan Chan?
Over rotation there on the forward one and a half sun assault.
1.6 the degree of difficulty.
The 17-year-old only competing in the 10-meter.
Still score this man in Singapore.
And he will rank 11 out of 11 after the first dives.
So this is how it stands after the first round.
Long way to go but T-Mail Bartel with a good dive, a difficult dive as well.
He's top of the rankings.
That's a long way to go for all these athletes and we're ready to go in this
Thank you.
Second round.
And we're going to get underway with the man who is second in the standings at the moment, the seventeen-year-old from the Ukraine in the eighteen in November.
Now an inward one and a half somersault.
Similar in difficulty to his first dive just to the degree of difficulty.
Possibly a touch of over rotation but he got the pike nicely.
Look at the effort.
All the flexibility the diver needs.
Just a little bit over perhaps.
But decent marks from the judges.
And 46 leaving there or thereabouts in the mix as we go through this preliminary round.
The big favourite, Yang Hao.
It'll ripple around this auditorium.
Inward one and a half somersault as well.
Same degree of difficulty as the Ukrainian.
The entry was better.
The coach likes it.
It's not quite as smart in the pike position.
But look at this entry.
And the judges have liked that one.
Look at that.
9.5s across the board.
57 to score.
And that's enough to put him into the lead early on in this second round.
A lot of divers to come.
Here's the next one.
Always Daniel Jensen.
Forward one and a half somersault.
A little bit over on the entry there.
Not as tighter by the sun we've seen.
Good in the pike.
Got to get out of that nice and early and then spot your landing.
Not too bad at all.
Judges.
More good in middling marks.
6.5s and 7s.
32.8.
He's not particularly happy.
Coach with a few words of wisdom for him.
Now Timo Bartel, who was in the mix, the double European junior champion last month.
What can he do here?
Decent dive.
Forward one and a half somersaults.
Stronger at the springboard if truth be told.
Fourth in that, which is a horrible position to come.
Just a little bit over rotating.
Tiny dive though.
And that's reflected in the judges scores.
33.6.
Not the most difficult dive.
So you've got to really nail these.
There's Saagisan.
Forward one and a half somersault.
1.6 the degree of difficulty.
he's only been in this 10 meter competition not the three meter long time to wait for his chance at the youth olympic games that's not quite getting straight on that entry into the water
into that right position and then not quite hitting the entry properly.
Again, reflected in the judges' scores.
Sevens in the 6.5, 32.8.
That'll put him into fifth place as we go through this second round of nine.
Now the Canadian, Philippe Gagnier.
The bronze medalist, of course, in the three metre.
Stronger on the platform, though.
Entry, that's not what he would have wanted, but the dive itself was pretty good.
Inward one and a half somersault.
Degree of difficulty is two, so that will help him a little bit.
Look at that, really tight on the pike.
A little bit untidy on that entry into the water, but the degree of difficulty helps him.
He gets 44 points, sevens from the judges.
Now, Egypt's Al Kordi, his coach by the way, is a professor of microbiology, not sure how that helps.
They're certainly enjoying themselves here at the Youth Olympic Games.
Simple dives, just a 1.8 degree of difficulty, but a fairly sharp and crisp dive.
from the 17 year old.
Pretty good entry.
7s and 6.5s, that's respectable for the Egyptian.
Now the Colombian, Kevin Garcia Alvarez.
A degree of difficulty of two and inward one and a half somersault here.
The youngest male diver at 15.
A little bit of over rotation as he entered the water.
He's not as sharp as he would like when he's executing the dive.
7 minutes 6.5, 6.5, 6.5, 6.5, 7 minutes 7.5, 4.5, 4.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5, 7.5,
He didn't get particularly tight on the pike, but a degree of difficulty will help him with the marks from the judges.
As crisp as I think he would have liked.
That element, nice, done quickly.
The entry, not impressing the judges overly.
He will go into fourth place already
20 points behind the Chinese athlete.
One of these first four dives, points carried forward to the final as well.
Alexis Zinda of France with an inward one and a half somersault.
Same dive we've just seen.
That looked pretty good to me.
Got the pike in nicely.
And the entry was pretty good as well.
Finished 12th of 12 in the 3 meter.
One dive went badly awry and that really put the kibosh on him.
But that's a very solid dive.
45 points for the Frenchman.
Now then, from Singapore with an inward one and a half somersault.
We've seen a few of these in this round to gain the degree of difficulty.
One of the elements of that was quite nice, but he didn't get the pike as crisp as he would have liked.
I think the entry will be marked down by the judges as well.
Concentration not that close his head to the fires But a decent set of marks from the judges seven and a half so you'll get 45 That'll drag him up into ninth place So that's the second round of nine
And it's going very well for the home fans who've turned up in fair numbers to see Yang Hao look for another gold medal here.
Just the preliminary rounds of course.
Egypt's Mohamed Al Kordi bringing up the rear.
But the long way to go here, remember four dives, the first four dives, there's a cap on the degree of difficulty.
These are the points that will be put forward into the final later on today.
So, seven rounds still to go in this plenary.
A long way to go.
A lot of important high degree of difficulty dives to come later on, so things can change quite quickly.
Philip Chakchenko of the Ukraine gets us underway in round three with a back dive.
Nicely done.
Simple, but if you nail it, it can be as effective as stumbling over a difficult dive.
Touching the toes, holding the position, and then looking for the entry points.
Look at that, eights.
1.8.5 struck off, so that's good from the Ukrainian.
He'll be happy with that.
Now here's the man who was top of the pile after the end of the second round.
Yang Hao, the man already has a gold at three meters with a reverse dive.
And that looked pretty good as well.
Pratt liked it of course.
A lot of people have arrived early here at the Natatorium to see this man.
He hasn't disappointed so far.
And race through impacts.
And look at that, a 10 from one of the judges.
You've had three 10s from the judges, 9.5s and 9s and that is a really, really good score.
Goodness me.
And he really is in form of 55-10, falling on for a really high score as well in the second round.
Timo Bartel, have to put that out of his mind and just get on with his dive.
Reverse, we're going to have some assault with a half twist.
And that was Daniel Jensen.
A slightly more straightforward dive than you would with one and a half somersault.
Getting ahead of myself there.
Not a bad entry from the Norwegian, the 18 year old.
Sevens and a score of 42.
Having put him into third place.
Now we have Timo Bartel.
And as I mentioned, not a difficult one this one.
2.1, the degree of difficulty, the reverse one, a half somersault, half twist.
And the entry wasn't great.
Maybe marked down for that.
It was a difficult dive though, so that will go in his favour.
Remember the middle three scores are taken and then it's multiplied by the degree of difficulty.
That's how we get our scores here.
Yeah, just a little bit of over rotation.
Six and a half are the scores that will count.
40.95 is the score that will be registered in this third round.
And then from Armenia, Lev Sayagisan.
competed in the World Championships, game 24th in the 10 metre event.
So he's mixing it with the men as well.
First arm stand we've seen and he held it well.
You have to show the judges that you're in control of the arm stand.
Forward somersault, the other component of the dive.
1.9, the degree of difficulty.
Didn't really get a tight pike in there.
The entry wasn't bad.
8s and 7.5s.
That's a decent score given the degree of difficulty.
And we've got him into fifth place.
On the platform now from Montreal as the divers seem to be from Canada.
Simple dive, the reverse dive.
1.9 the degree of difficulty.
The position with the hands on the five for quite a while before you snap back into the entry position.
Seven and a halfs.
There was a couple of eights.
They were struck off.
Forty-two point seven five into fourth place at the moment for a man from Canada.
Now the Egyptian.
Picking up the rankings at the moment.
What can you do here with this reverse dive?
A little untidy entry.
Going to see two divers at this Youth Olympic Games from the Egyptians.
They have limited training.
Training in the winter in Egypt.
No indoor pool for them to practice in.
Not liked by the judges at all.
A bit untidy.
5.5 and 6 is 29.45.
And these of course are the points that have been taken forward to the final.
The first four dives.
Kevin Garcia Alvarez of Columbia.
10th in the three metre competition.
Reverse dive here.
A little untidy on the entry.
Simple dive, so you've got to get it right.
Otherwise your mistakes will be amplified as the scores are multiplied to get our point score.
Oh, not too bad.
He'll be happy enough with seven and seven and a halfs.
1.8, 1.6, 1.5, there's truck through, of course.
Now this is a man who needs to start nailing some dives.
There you go, Diego Lopez, reverse dive, simple dive.
Well, not too bad.
Getting cheers from the crowd.
I wonder whether the judges will be overly impressed in that white position.
Need to get your head right up against your legs in order to do that.
Another bad entry.
Sevens, seven and a halfs across the board.
It's enough to put him into third place.
Next up, the Frenchman meets Jeandard.
Another reverse dive.
One of these simple dives early on.
The degree of difficulty has been capped.
Gain.
Setting the world on fire with that dive.
He disgraced himself.
need to have a really tight tuck in that pike and a tidy entry and not as high as you would like six and a half and sevens but eight point nine five enough to put him into sixth place at the moment two point one the difficulty here a reverse half somersault half twist i've seen this before in this round so a difficult one for the singaporean
Well, elegantly done, but the entry wasn't great.
As crisp as the judges were hoping for.
Right, they're going in to this round.
A little bit of over rotation, not hugely liked by the judges.
Sixes, there was one 5.5 in there and he is down in tenth at the moment as we conclude that third round and it's good news for everyone who's crammed in here.
155.3 for Yan Hao and quite a bit of difference through him and Pidit Tychenko.
And then a very close between third, fourth, fifth.
And then it's a little bit of a distance, certainly when you get down to tenth, Jonathan Chan and Moab Abkordi, the Egyptian in 11th.
Over 50, 60 points, the difference already after three rounds between top and bottom.
Great to see so many people coming in for the preliminary rounds.
Enjoying what they can see.
Headphones are off for some of these athletes.
There's our professor of microbiology.
Having a chat to his child.
Vyachenko of Ukraine ready to go.
Fifth and three meter has had more success.
Second after three rounds.
This will be a reverse dive.
Last round of course where the difficulty is kept.
That looked pretty good.
Certainly got that pike nice and tight.
Touching the knees, that's what you want to see.
Holding the hands against the legs and then bringing them around.
Tidy but not spectacular.
Sevens almost across the board from the judges.
39.9 momentarily.
Here we go into the lead.
And then a ripple around this athletic centre.
Younghow has a difficult dive this one, the forward one and a half somersault and one twist.
Well, it was good.
Not so good into the water.
He scored consistently well.
Over 50 points in the first or the second and third dives.
And he's going to do the same again here.
56.7 nines.
Mostly from the judges.
And he really is setting down the marker, isn't he?
Another Norwegian, Daniel Jensen.
Difficult time for him as well.
A little bit of over rotation when he came into the water.
The element in the air looked pretty good as well.
2.1, the degree of difficulty.
Got to get into the dive quickly, get all the elements out of the way.
A little bit too soon into that dive position, perhaps.
But, given the degree of difficulty, he does alright.
6.5, the scores that count.
14.95, we'll see him third at the moment.
Just a simple reverse dive.
Difficulty of 1.9.
They're all
Not as tight as he might like into the pike.
And a pretty straight entry into the water.
Judges like it.
It was one nine.
Eight point fives and an eight.
Forty-eight point four five.
That's decent.
That will push him into third place.
Lev Sagisan.
Next up of Armenia.
Forward.
One twist.
Two point one the degree of difficulty.
Little bit early into the water, not quite going in vertically.
The 10 metre specialist, let's see this entry here.
Not too bad, 6.5s from the judges, 40.95 he goes into fifth.
French-Canadian man from Montreal, Philippe Gagnet.
That wasn't too bad.
For the winner of half somersault, one twist.
Free position.
I'm going to get into that pike position.
early into the somersault some twist and perhaps just a little bit of over rotation that's why he's not got outstanding mark sevens okay 44.1 we'll see him go into fourth place
Now the Egyptian with the arms down, forward, double somersault, this a 2.4 degree of difficulty so he's had the simple dies but now he's really going to go for it.
Had low marks before, 29.45, he'll be looking for better here.
Well, he didn't hold it in the arms down for long enough.
The judges need to see that you've got that under control, and you will be punished for that.
But once you're going, you're going.
And Campbell's somersault is certainly there.
Given the degree of difficulty, he's been marked.
OK, 6, 5.5, 40.8.
For the time being, he's up into seventh place.
But there are, of course, four more divers to go in this fourth round.
Kevin Garcia Alvarez.
This is a tricky dive back.
One twist, half a twist rather.
The difficulty is two.
Double tidy this entry into the water.
It's particularly tight in the dive here.
Let's have a look at this entry.
Not quite getting it right, not quite in that lovely vertical position we like to see, but given the degree of difficulty he's done alright, a score of 4-2-1.
Into sixth place he goes.
And the Mexican needs a good dive here.
And that's not a bad one.
Forward, one and a half, somersault, one twist.
2.1 of the degree of difficulty.
Look at the effort.
The amount of effort you see on the face.
Let's look at this entry.
It wasn't too bad at all.
Respectable.
But all that standing from Diego Lopez.
He'd have been hoping for better.
He goes into equal third place with Timo Barthes.
But he's 42 points behind.
Back one and a half somersault, half twist on the Frenchman.
And it's the gendarme.
Of course, we have the luxury of looking at the replay and making our judgements.
The judges, of course, look at it live, make their decision.
Sevens and a 7.5 for the Frenchman.
Into sixth place he goes.
Just one more athlete to go in this fourth round and that is Jonathan Chan of Singapore with an arm stand forward somersault.
And the switch from gymnastics at the age of 12.
He should be able to nail this arm stand with nothing else.
Big splash on the entry to the dive.
He wouldn't be particularly happy with that.
1.9 the degree of difficulty.
But he held that lovely, didn't he, for an honest long time.
Fives from the judges, didn't like the entry, particularly 28 and a half points.
He's down in 10th place.
Well, it's going well for Yan Hao.
Look at the difference between him and Tchaikovsky.
Look at the battle for second and third and fourth.
Very tight.
Less than five points between those athletes.
And then it's the battle for the rest.
And it's quite tight at the bottom between Chan and El-Kory.
They'll be having their own personal battle down there at the bottom of the rankings.
Into the fifth round, and the cap on the degree of difficulty goes away.
These scores aren't carried forward to the final, but it is where we get the spectacular dives.
So, Ochenko with a forward three and a half somersault.
Beg your pardon, backward two and a half somersault, one and a half twists.
A little dive coming later.
As you can see, the crowd enjoying the step-up in difficulty.
Real test for these young athletes.
And the twisting into the sun salts.
Not a bad entry.
Middling scores from the judges.
65.6 though, given the degree of difficulty.
We'll see the scores going up.
We'll have to put him obviously ahead just for the time being.
Now then, what can we see from the Chinese diver?
Inward three and a half somersault.
3.2.
The degree of difficulty.
Oh, a big cheer from the crowd.
Got to get into those somersaults as quickly as you possibly can to give you enough time to sight the entry into the water.
Look at the effort.
coming out looking that's not a bad entry is it not as good as some of his other scores eights from the judges but given the degree of difficulty the score 76.8 is 48 points ahead at the top at the moment now Daniel Jensen seventh in the three meter and they're consistent there no major mistakes and we haven't seen many
here either forward three and a half somersault degree of difficulty is three he didn't hit the entry at all well under rotated and he will be punished by the judges for that
so difficult you've got to concentrate first of all on getting these semisoles out of the way and then he just didn't have enough time to get the dive in and that's why he's getting low marks from the judges five and a half and five so he'll be disappointed with that Timo Barthel of Germany third after round four in a very tight battle
I understand that double somersault was one and a half twists.
3.2 which is really difficult.
Again, a little bit lacking in time to get into that dive position to get into the water.
Really got to be quick into the somersaults.
struggling for time to sight that dive a little bit under rotated six and a halfs and sixes from the judges that may give some of his rivals around looking for first second third place some opportunity there he's disappointed with that of course these points not being pushed forward into the final
Three and a half.
Seven salts.
Okay, not great on the entry.
Had it for a very long time on the 10-meter platform.
Really got to get the somersaults out of the way as quickly as possible because you're running out of air.
Sixes, six and a half for that inward three and a half somersault.
Four left.
Saiga-san, 60.8.
Into fourth place he goes.
Philippe Gagne of Canada.
Another inward three and a half somersault.
Same as we saw from the Armenian with Saigetan.
And if anything, over rotated on that.
Not quite hitting the entries here, the athletes at the moment.
A bit untidy with the feet as well.
And he's been marked down as a result.
Six years in the 6.5 into fourth place for the Canadian.
And Quebec.
Well, the Egyptian going for a forward three and a half somersault.
A difficulty of three.
Let's see how he does here.
The very rotation on entry.
given the lack of resources he has to put up with in his home country in terms of poor his extra work sixes from the judges over rotation as you can see he entered the water 54 the score into seventh place for the time being but expecting to drop backwards as we go now the Colombian Kevin Garcia Alvarez prefers the platform dives
Gaining a little bit of over rotation on that three and a half somersault.
Very quick getting through the somersaults.
She didn't have enough time just to sight the entry there.
Great flexibility these athletes have.
Six and a halfs and sevens.
Sixty the score.
And you can see him there just indicating to his coach, a little bit over on the entry.
Third place after the last round.
Again, a little bit of a rotation from the next man.
All struggling a little bit on these more complex dives.
And there you go.
There you go, Lopez.
Not getting himself really tight into that pike.
The over rotation means it's a disappointment for him.
5.5 and 6.
He's billed as a big rival to Jan Reha, but at the moment he is in fifth place.
Remember, of course, how the points for the first four dives go forward to the final.
This is, for a moment, like a glorified practice for all these guys.
Didn't hit the entry at all well.
It's the Chanda, and the France, four, three and a half somersault.
The somersault's all right.
Ran out of time to get in and ready for entering the water.
Falls and he can't have any complaints about that.
Down into ninth he goes.
You can see from the truthful smile he knew what the problem was.
Jonathan Chan then in his own personal battle at the moment with El Cordi at the bottom of the rankings.
Good turn off some sorts with a twist.
Well, not the worst dive we've seen, but again entry.
Outstanding.
There's a few Singaporeans here in the crowd.
You can probably hear them cheering.
He liked what they saw.
The judge is not so impressed.
Not so bad on the entry.
Sixes.
from the judges and he still stays ahead by about four points from the Egyptian in that battle not to be bottom.
Interesting at the top though look at the difference between first and second but then the battle between second third
It's quite tight and between fourth and fifth as well.
And there's that personal battle between Chan and Al Kordi at the bottom.
And Xandar will be disappointedly down there as well.
196.55 points.
So, fifth round, done and dusted.
We move on to round six of nine.
Getting through this in good order.
They're waiting for Ukranian Filip Tlachenko to get us underway.
Seventh in the Olympic Games qualifier.
Not all the athletes who qualified in that qualifier here.
Gave the country the right to be here.
Forward three and a half somersaults then.
A man who was second after the last round.
Quite nailing the entry there.
It was so quick to get these somersaults out of the way and then quickly look at where you're going to land and it was over rotated.
Six, six and a halfs.
At the moment no one is touching the next diver on the platform.
Here he is.
and how back three and a half somersault 3.3 the degree of difficulty he's ahead by a country mile at the moment
Big cheer from the crowd, this is the guy of course who has scored a 10.
from these judges he is enjoying his games at the moment already has a goal in the three meter and that was not bad at all was it decent entry as well and nines and eight and a half from the judges 85.8 the score and he is heading towards a hundred point advantage of his rivals
Daniel Jensen then on the reverse, two and a half somersault for the Norwegian.
2.8 the degree of difficulty, so not the most difficult dive you'll see in these latter stages.
Jensen medaled in the European Junior Championships.
He has competed at world and European Championship level as well.
And the experience shown through there with eights and seven and a halfs.
Into third place he goes.
Timo Bartelnik is a German athlete.
He's in the three metre platform.
Looking for better here.
Ooh, the feet weren't at all right.
Under-rotated, a little bit under-cooked.
You can see there's a right angle between the body and the legs as he tries to nail this in with three and a half somersault.
This is the bit that's going to concern the judges.
And as a result, he's marked down.
Five and a halfs, 52.8 is disappointing for the German.
Now the Armenian Lev Sygeson.
Seventh at the European Junior Championships this year in the 10 meter board.
Here's her back, three and a half somersault.
Well, it was a 3.6 degree of difficulty.
That's the most difficult you're going to see in these preliminary rounds.
He's got two of them in his routine.
And that wasn't a bad effort.
A little bit of over rotation.
And that's why the judges have marked him down.
Fives and five and a half as well.
Still getting a half decent score because of that degree of difficulty, but he'll be disappointed.
3.3 degree of difficulty now for the Canadian, Philippe Gagne.
3.5 to 7 salt.
Entry's a little bit undercut.
Not sure, a little bit under-rotated there.
Such a learning curve for these athletes.
Into that tuck position, knees up to the chest.
Well, oh disaster, that's for sure.
Six and a halfs from the judges.
64.35 into third place for the Canadian.
We'll have El Cordi of YouTube next up and in with three and a half somersault, 3.2 the degree of difficulty.
A little bit untidy, a bit of over rotation.
But it's great to see him here along with Mahagouda.
Two Egyptians taking part in these Youth Olympic Games.
Fives and five and a halfs.
The judges have decided.
51.2 the score.
And Terri into seventh place.
Now the Colombian, Kevin Garcia Alvarez.
Stronger on the platform.
In with three and a half somersault, 3.2 the degree of difficulty.
Just a little bit over rotated on the entry.
But not bad marks on the judges.
Seven and a half and he'll be happy with that score which puts him into fourth place.
Now this man needs to step up to the mark a little bit.
In Mexico we've been talking him up but at the moment he's just struggling a little bit.
The coach likes it.
He's a long way away from Yang Hao and even some of the other divers.
Better from him.
Sevens and seven and a halfs from our judges.
70.4.
Will it be enough to put him into third place?
Now the Frenchman.
and uh last time i didn't enjoy that okay do this in with three and a half semisault again
Not a great entry into the water.
He's struggling a little bit with his dives.
Just 16 years of age, not 17 until October.
Of course, for the Youth Olympic Games, you hit that four-year cycle.
If you're 18, you've got a slight advantage, I think it's fair to say.
Sevens and there's six and a half.
Well, not too bad.
Frenchman into ninth place.
He's likely to stay
Nathan Chan now with a forward three and a half somersault.
Three point degree of difficulty.
It's not too bad.
A little bit untidy into the water.
The Singaporean contingent.
Happy to give him every support they can.
Good position on that pike.
Just a little bit over rotated.
And six and a half's not too bad for Chan, the man from Singapore.
in year five at the ACS school in Singapore.
So he's still a student, only competing in the 10 meter.
And you know how, look at that, look at the difference between first and second, and look how close it is between second, third, well all the way down to sixth really.
Orca change in the next three dives.
Nine rounds of course.
And a decent battle at the bottom as well between the Frenchman, the Singaporean and the man from Egypt.
So, three more dives to go.
For each athlete and a chance to show what they can do with some really eye-catching dives.
The man who is first of the eleven to go.
months ago, competed in the European Junior Championships 12th in the 10 meter platform event there 6th in the 1 meter as well this one, inward, 3.5 somersaults 3.2 degree of difficulty
Not too bad.
Perfect entry into the water.
There's the bounce.
A push away from the platform.
Not a bad entry either.
The judges like it.
8.5 scrub through.
76.8.
He's been there, all thereabouts, all the way through, so that he wasn't match Yang Hao.
Here he is, the home favourite.
3.4 degree of difficulty.
This reverse, three and a half sunsault.
Difficult dives coming over, next one will be 3.5 for him, so he needs to nail these.
Didn't look too bad from here.
it's an awful long way down there's a lot of things that can go wrong but he is looking in a class of his own at the moment getting nice and tight in that tuck position early into the dive and what a beautiful entry as well and nines from the judges one nine point five
One judge with an 8.5, a couple with 8.5, 91.8.
Well, he is edging very, very closely to an advantage of over 100 points.
Dunbar-Hensen now.
Inward, three and a half somersaults for him.
Oh, he didn't get into the water at all, well there.
Still looking to extend the legs and didn't manage it, he knows it.
Look at that little look of dismay.
Not too pretty on replay either.
Chetty will mark him down on that, he'll mark him way down as well.
And he's got the ability.
bronze in the European Junior Championships this year.
Oh dear, four and three and a halfs.
Very consistent in the three meter, no major mistakes, but that's one there.
They'll be hoping to get that out of the system before the finals later on.
Of course, these more complex dives don't count towards, don't carry forward.
The first four dives are, so it's not a disaster.
Gaining the entry, not perfect.
And that back three and a half semisault.
Tricky dive, 3.3 the degree of difficulty.
Stronger on the springboard.
Oh disaster those sevens.
Now the scores he'll take through, 69.3.
Into third place he goes.
Good battle for second, third and fourth.
And there's Saiga-san of Armenia.
That's a reverse three and a half somersault.
Three point four is a degree of difficulty, so if you can get this right, you'll score well.
Well, not quite nailing the entry, but almost saying a fairly tidy dive.
You want to make sure you've got that clearance, of course, from the platform.
Good push out.
Get the somersaults out of the way.
Make sure you've got time to site your entry.
The entry, I think, was probably the problem.
Sevens almost across the board, bottom one, six point five, into fourth place for the Armenian.
And he was fourth in this competition going into this round.
Armstand back double somersault with one and a half twist.
It's a tricky one this.
Well a bit of difficulty holding the armstand.
you need to make sure that's under control you'll be marked down otherwise by the judges looking to get the acrobatic element out of the way as soon as possible so you can sight that entry into the water a little bit untidy into the water and six and a half and sixes for Gagne he will stay in fourth place
No, Mohab Al Kordi, one of the athletes, it comes to the spirit of the Youth Olympic Games.
He's not going to medal, but he is going to give it everything.
It's a two and a half, full two and a half somersault with two twists.
And two untied.
The entry wasn't the greatest, but it was a degree of difficulty of 3.3.
A bit hurried through the elements, and the hands at the end of the water.
He's also not particularly ready.
And fours and four and a halfs.
Well, you know, it was all experience for this guy.
17 years of age.
And here is a 15-year-old, not 16 until next month.
The Colombian.
And there's Garcia.
A little bit undercooked going in.
Under-rotated on that back three and a half somersault.
Difficult dive.
Come on, whip the arms round.
Quicker than that, but not the disaster.
Sevens from the judges.
That's good enough to put him into third place, keep him in third place.
And the Mexican has been a bit off form, I think it's fair to say, today.
The armstand back triple somersault.
And from Guadalajara.
In the three metre youth Olympic Games qualifying event.
I think it's fair to say he looks more comfortable at three metre.
the silver in the three meter so we thought he was going to be one of those up and running and looking for a medal here but not so sure what's going to happen we get to the finals tonight sixes a little bit as he was telling his coach undercooked that dive now Alexis Janda
going into this round seventh of nine of course back two and a half somersault not the most difficult we've seen in this round oh well don't need me to tell you you hit that horribly into the water you mark down and then some blind the judges so that tuck position
Well, nearly an incomplete dive.
Just about got away with it.
The judges will not be going easy on him.
Three and a halfs heard here.
Wanted to forget the move on.
Now then, here's Jonathan Chan, a youngster, a former gymnast.
And then inward, three and a half semisoles.
A little bit early on the entry.
We're seeing a few ragged dives.
In a way it doesn't matter because this is all about the ranking for the final.
It's a good time to get these ragged edges shaved off again.
Very, very early on the entry.
Under-rotated by quite some distance.
Fours and four and a halfs.
As we said, only the first four dives, the easier dives, the points go forward.
Look at the difference here, almost a hundred points between Yang and Pechenko, but much tighter, look at that, between third, fourth, fifth and sixth.
And then a private battle at the bottom between Jensen Chan, Yandar and Elm Kordi.
to see who the rankings are for the final no doubt who's going to be ranked number one some of the athletes just locking off the noise with some headphones as we head towards the penultimate round round eight of nine here
Here is Tachenko, a man who seems to do better over three meters.
He's always been there or thereabouts.
But he's doing better here.
Ranked second going into this eighth round.
A tricky old dive here.
It was a good hold but again the entry wasn't perfect.
3.2 the degree of difficulty.
Armstand back double somersault with one and a half twists.
Just a little bit of this entry, just a little bit over rotated.
Sixes from the judges, 57.6.
He has been consistently the best of the rest after this man.
This is his biggest dive.
3.5 is a degree of difficulty and Armstrong back triple somersault.
He'll take his time over this.
Oh, the entry wasn't great.
Degree of difficulty.
We'll put some pressure on this young man.
A 16-year-old.
Look at that perfect pike position.
but over-rotated and the crowd didn't like what they saw from the judges and I'm sure Young won't either.
Fours and the coach straight in to have a word.
Well that might chip away at the advantage.
Now Janssen off Norway.
Relatively simple back two and a half sunsets.
A bit undercooked on the entry.
A little bit under-rotated.
He'll be punished for that.
They've only got the bronze in the European Junior Championships in the 10m, but that's not the best type he'll ever do.
A little bit early into the water.
Fours.
Judges are getting serious here.
Next up, Germany's team out.
European junior champion last month.
This completely different.
Of course.
oh dear didn't hit that one at all slapped to the back of the legs as he entered the water and once again we see a round of low scores here here's a long session we do oh dear that's ugly everywhere you look at it long session will these divers be tiring
That's an excellent experience for them.
It's not an excellent score for Thibaut Bartel, who has Sandro just marking down at three.
Well, will it be better for Lev Saag-Sand?
Seventh going into this round.
The arm stand back, double sun assault, one and a half twists, 3.2 the degree of difficulty.
The entry wasn't too bad.
He fell off the platform.
A lot of attack in the dive.
Here's the push to get the momentum.
Not too bad.
He's certainly marking that better than the last couple of dives.
Six and a half, 62.4, enough to put him into third place after Bartel's disappointing dive.
Now the Canadian Philippe Gagné.
Reverse three and a half somersault.
This is a difficult die.
3.4 the degree of difficulty.
An over rotation this time.
Really difficult.
These guys are finding it difficult in this eighth round to nail these
These dives, I don't know whether it's timeliness or it's concentration, or perhaps just inexperience, of course, we forget.
These are young divers, of course.
Four and a halfs and a five, and it's enough to push him up into fourth place.
Saiga-san is in third after a better-than-the-rest dive.
And the Egyptian, Mohab El-Kourly.
A little bit of rotation, but given his inexperience he'll be happy with that.
3.3, the degree of difficulty.
Hasn't been scoring heavily in the latter rounds.
Look at the effort.
Certainly gives it a go, not scared.
Only threes from the judges, almost across the board.
1-4, he's just struck off.
He's not like that at all.
I wonder if the shorter attention span, the shorter focus you need in the final will help.
Only five rounds of course, nine rounds here.
This one a bit more of a marathon than a sprint.
Alvarez next up, the Colombian.
There we go, as long as you can control that, it's done alright.
five there's no great shakes but he got away with it well if you have to come back down and reset again the dive you automatically lose two points so he didn't want to do that fair play to him
There's more athletic ability in the gymnastic department than most of us can muster.
A little bit of over rotation in the entry into the water.
But, well, considering what we've seen in this round before, he'll be happy with 5.5s.
Coming into third place.
Now then, here's the Mexican, Rodrigo Diego Lopez.
Fifth at the moment.
and didn't hit the entry at all well we've seen that a little bit in this eighth round the legs getting a slap of water he did a slap and snap the legs over but given the degree of difficulty 5.5 and 6 he's dropped down in the last couple of rounds
That's enough to put him up into third place at the moment, given the free-for-all we've had in this round.
36s and 30s from Jeanne d'Art.
A couple of poor scoring rounds.
He's improving slowly.
That was okay.
The back two and a half somersaults with one and a half twists in that pike position.
Didn't really in a tight pike position but the judges were satisfied enough.
Sevens and six and a halfs.
Sixty-four.
Puts it up into eighth place.
ahead of Daniel Jensen and Jonathan Chan will be looking for enough points certainly to get him ahead of the Egyptian Al Corly and possibly near to Daniel Jensen and simple dive 2.8 difficulty and he's reversed two and a half somersaults so a tidy enough dive
The greatest entry into the water.
Big cheers to him near that diving platform.
The Singaporean contingent are giving him every encouragement.
He's represented Singapore at the Asian Youth Games.
Untidy going into the water.
He'll be punished as well.
Five and a halfs.
Still ahead of the Egyptian though.
And then touching distance of Daniel Jensen.
In what is the preliminary of course to sort out the rankings going into the final.
Everyone will make it to the final.
Not losing anybody.
And with a disappointing eighth dive.
But very close in the midfield between third, fourth, fifth, and even sixth as well.
They're coming dry some day to the Youth Olympic Games.
We have certainly enjoyed their enthusiastic support.
And a really good turnout here again in this atatorium.
Just part of the Olympic Sports Centre.
Fabulous.
Appointed Sports Centre.
Tough round the eighth one, only two getting into the 60 points.
A lot of mistakes being made, a lot of high difficulty, degree of difficulty dives of course as well and if you can nail them then it's amplified in the score of course as we said the middle three scores count then they're added together and multiplied by the degree of difficulty so if you can get a half decent score with a difficult dive then you're doing okay.
Now this man is doing okay, second
at the moment as we go into our last round of dives.
The ninth round to Tchenko.
3.3 the degree of difficulty here so he has a chance to do well.
That's not too bad.
Entry a little bit wanting.
Three and a half sun assaults.
And that tuck position, the tightest tuck you'll ever see.
A little bit twisted as he went in on that entry, and that wall, yes, it's been punished by the judges.
We have the sharpest of sharp eyes, don't need a replay to pick out the faults.
So Yang showed he was fallible in that last round, just 42 points.
What can he do here?
That's better.
And the current moment as well.
3.2 the degree of difficulty for that fact.
Two and a half somersault with one and a half twists.
Nice entry as well.
Look at the scores as well.
Coming through from the judges.
Nine and a halfs and nines.
Back on form for Younghow.
Just a reminder if anyone thought he had a little bit of fallibility about him after the eighth round that it doesn't matter.
I can still pull it back.
So then.
Daniel Jensen with his last dive.
3.2 the degree of difficulty.
Back two and a half sets with one and a half twists.
Another great entry.
That's in the 18-year-old seaside town.
Horton in Norway, 100 kilometres from Oslo.
Norway from home at the moment.
62.4 for the man from Norway.
Now the German, Timo Bartell,
Standing seventh.
A bit of an under-rotator going in on that back two and a half somersault with one and a half twists.
3.2 the difficulty.
Nice entry, though.
Sixes, six and a halfs from the judges.
59.2.
Into third place momentarily.
One of these guys qualifying, of course, for a final round.
It's the large field you might see at the Olympics.
Just 11.
It's going to be 12.
We're down to 11.
Lev Sargasan of Armenia.
3.6, the degree of difficulty here.
If he can do well here, he will score very heavily.
He always takes his time at the top of the platform.
and that's not at all bad given the complexity of that back two and a half somersaults two and a half twists in the point position nicely done
So then, the Canadian, Philippe Gagne.
3.2, the degree of difficulty.
Let's have a look at this dive now.
A little bit of over rotation there.
The judge is a little bit forgiving.
60s, that was 1.7 there.
So then the Egyptian Moab El Kordi.
His last dive of this competition.
A 3.4, so a difficult dive.
Reverse three and a half somersault.
Difficult dives in this last round.
Well, you know what?
Not the greatest dive, but he's done so well.
He's competed hard here.
Got the somersaults in.
Not a great entry into the water.
Held the position well.
Not a bad entry.
And a couple of fives from the judges.
They'll be struck off.
44.2 is the score there.
And he's pleased enough.
He certainly is showing promise to the Egyptian.
Kevin Garcia Alvarez.
Colombian.
Fourth going into this last round.
Slightly uneven arm balance there.
Something he always does a little bit.
Untidy entry into the water.
Two and a half somersaults, one and a half twists.
a little bit over rotated but not bad marks from the judges who quite like what they see 3.2 the degree of difficulty so the sevens will give them a decent score now then a 3.6 degree of difficulty a couple of those in this round for the Mexican Rodrigo Diego Lopez back two and a half somersault two and a half twists
Just about got away with it.
Had to get the hurry on to get that entry in.
Danger of being completely under-rotated on entry.
That's not a half bad dive.
Difficult, difficult dive to do.
The judges have marked him round about seven.
That's a decent score of 75.6.
That puts him up into third place.
That's better from the Mexican.
He's languished in the mid rankings for quite some time.
Alexis Jandard next up.
Two more dives in this preliminary round on the 10 meter platform.
This is a 3.2 degree difficulty.
An arm stand back double somersault with a one and a half twist.
And the entry not great.
Edwin undercoats.
You have to hold it in that arm stand for quite some time.
And then when you go, go hard and go quickly.
Not too bad.
Sevens across the board apart from that 1.6.5.
67.2 for Alexis Jandard.
Next up, Jonathan Chan, the youngster, the student from Singapore.
3.3 the difficulty for this back three and a half sunsock.
A little bit under rotated.
Difficult dive for Chan.
That's a really good and interesting dives and a much better quality of diving in this 9th round compared to the 8th round.
Little bit under-rotated and as a result, four and a halfs and fives for Chad.
Just enough to take him ahead of El Cordi.
Of course, all these companies qualifying and they're just sorting out the rankings here.
And these are the rankings.
Look, over a hundred points the difference between Yang and left Saiga-san.
Real quality from Yang at the top end.
Saiga-san had a good comeback from Diego Lopez as well.
Tight between all those.
García Álvarez not far away either.
And Tijenco dropped away towards the end.
China, I think it's fair to say, on course for that double-double of gold medals.
That's the preliminaries out of the way.
The final comes later.
The fans here have enjoyed these nine rounds of diving.
And Yang Hao has given the local support something to cheer about.
Some absolutely fabulous dives.
Some tens in there as well.
And they'll be pleased with how it's gone for China this morning in the preliminary competition.
Thank you very much.
Some great action here then in the preliminaries.
What is clear is that Yang Hao, the Chinese diver, is the man to try and catch as we head towards the finals of this 10 meter platform competition.